"To do two things at once is to do neither."
[AI] “同时做两件事等于什么也不做。”
It's a great smackdown of multitasking. isn't it.
[AI] 这是一个伟大的多任务处理。不是吗。
often attributed to the Roman writer Publilius Syrus.
[AI] 通常被认为是罗马作家普布利乌斯·西卢斯的作品。
although you know how these things are. he probably never said it.
[AI] 虽然你知道这些事情是怎样的。他可能从来没有说过。
What I'm interested in. though. is -- is it true?
[AI] 我感兴趣的是什么。虽然是真的吗？
I mean. it's obviously true for emailing at the dinner table
[AI] 我是说。在餐桌上发电子邮件显然是正确的
or texting while driving or possibly for live tweeting at TED Talk. as well.
[AI] 或者开车时发短信，或者可能在TED Talk现场发推特。也
But I'd like to argue that for an important kind of activity.
[AI] 但我想说的是，这是一种重要的活动。
doing two things at once -- or three or even four --
[AI] 同时做两件事——或者三件甚至四件--
is exactly what we should be aiming for.
[AI] 这正是我们应该追求的目标。
Look no further than Albert Einstein.
[AI] 看看阿尔伯特·爱因斯坦就知道了。
In 1905. he published four remarkable scientific papers.
[AI] 1905年。他发表了四篇杰出的科学论文。
One of them was on Brownian motion.
[AI] 其中一个是布朗运动。
it provided empirical evidence that atoms exist.
[AI] 它提供了原子存在的经验证据。
and it laid out the basic mathematics behind most of financial economics.
[AI] 它还列出了大多数金融经济学背后的基础数学。
Another one was on the theory of special relativity.
[AI] 另一个是狭义相对论。
Another one was on the photoelectric effect.
[AI] 另一个是关于光电效应。
that's why solar panels work. it's a nice one.
[AI] 这就是太阳能电池板工作的原因。很好。
Gave him the Nobel prize for that one.
[AI] 因为那件事给了他诺贝尔奖。
And the fourth introduced an equation you might have heard of:
[AI] 第四个介绍了一个你可能听说过的方程式：
E equals mc squared.
[AI] E等于mc的平方。
So. tell me again how you shouldn't do several things at once.
[AI] 所以再告诉我一次，你不应该同时做几件事。
Now. obviously. working simultaneously
[AI] 现在明显地同时工作
on Brownian motion. special relativity and the photoelectric effect --
[AI] 关于布朗运动。狭义相对论与光电效应--
it's not exactly the same kind of multitasking
[AI] 这和多任务处理不完全一样
as Snapchatting while you're watching "Westworld."
[AI] 当你在看《西世界》的时候聊天
Very different.
[AI] 非常不同。
And Einstein. yeah. well. Einstein's -- he's Einstein.
[AI] 还有爱因斯坦。是 啊好爱因斯坦，他是爱因斯坦。
he's one of a kind. he's unique.
[AI] 他是独一无二的。他是独一无二的。
But the pattern of behavior that Einstein was demonstrating.
[AI] 但是爱因斯坦证明的行为模式。
that's not unique at all.
[AI] 这一点也不独特。
It's very common among highly creative people.
[AI] 这在富有创造力的人中很常见。
both artists and scientists.
[AI] 艺术家和科学家。
and I'd like to give it a name:
[AI] 我想给它起个名字：
slow-motion multitasking.
[AI] 慢动作多任务处理。
Slow-motion multitasking feels like a counterintuitive idea.
[AI] 慢动作多任务处理感觉像是一个违反直觉的想法。
What I'm describing here
[AI] 我在这里描述的是什么
is having multiple projects on the go at the same time.
[AI] 正在同时进行多个项目。
and you move backwards and forwards between topics as the mood takes you.
[AI] 随着情绪的变化，你会在不同的话题之间来回移动。
or as the situation demands.
[AI] 或者视情况而定。
But the reason it seems counterintuitive
[AI] 但其原因似乎违反直觉
is because we're used to lapsing into multitasking out of desperation.
[AI] 因为我们习惯于在绝望中一心多用。
We're in a hurry. we want to do everything at once.
[AI] 我们赶时间。我们想同时做每件事。
If we were willing to slow multitasking down.
[AI] 如果我们愿意放慢多任务处理的速度。
we might find that it works quite brilliantly.
[AI] 我们可能会发现它工作得相当出色。
Sixty years ago. a young psychologist by the name of Bernice Eiduson
[AI] 六十年前。一位名叫伯尼斯·艾杜森的年轻心理学家
began a long research project
[AI] 开始了一项长期的研究项目
into the personalities and the working habits
[AI] 进入性格和工作习惯
of 40 leading scientists.
[AI] 由40位顶尖科学家组成。
Einstein was already dead.
[AI] 爱因斯坦已经死了。
but four of her subjects won Nobel prizes.
[AI] 但她的四个研究对象获得了诺贝尔奖。
including Linus Pauling and Richard Feynman.
[AI] 包括莱纳斯·鲍林和理查德·费曼。
The research went on for decades.
[AI] 这项研究持续了几十年。
in fact. it continued even after professor Eiduson herself had died.
[AI] 事实上即使在艾杜森教授本人去世后，这种情况仍在继续。
And one of the questions that it answered
[AI] 它回答了一个问题
was. "How is it that some scientists are able to go on producing important work
[AI] 是“为什么有些科学家能够继续进行重要的研究？”
right through their lives?"
[AI] 就在他们的一生中？"
What is it about these people?
[AI] 这些人是怎么回事？
Is it their personality. is it their skill set.
[AI] 这是他们的个性。这是他们的技能。
their daily routines. what?
[AI] 他们的日常生活。什么
Well. a pattern that emerged was clear. and I think to some people surprising.
[AI] 好出现的模式是明确的。我觉得有些人很惊讶。
The top scientists kept changing the subject.
[AI] 顶尖的科学家们不断地变换话题。
They would shift topics repeatedly
[AI] 他们会反复转移话题
during their first 100 published research papers.
[AI] 在他们发表的前100篇研究论文中。
Do you want to guess how often?
[AI] 你想知道多久一次吗？
Three times?
[AI] 三次？
Five times?
[AI] 五次？
No. On average. the most enduringly creative scientists
[AI] 不，平均来说。最有创造力的科学家
switched topics 43 times in their first 100 research papers.
[AI] 在他们的前100篇研究论文中交换了43次主题。
Seems that the secret to creativity is multitasking
[AI] 似乎创造力的秘诀在于多任务处理
in slow motion.
[AI] 慢动作。
Eiduson's research suggests we need to reclaim multitasking
[AI] 艾杜森的研究表明，我们需要回收多任务
and remind ourselves how powerful it can be.
[AI] 提醒自己它有多强大。
And she's not the only person to have found this.
[AI] 她不是唯一发现这个的人。
Different researchers.
[AI] 不同的研究人员。
using different methods to study different highly creative people
[AI] 用不同的方法研究不同的有创造力的人
have found that very often they have multiple projects in progress
[AI] 发现他们经常有多个正在进行的项目
at the same time.
[AI] 同时
and they're also far more likely than most of us to have serious hobbies.
[AI] 他们也比我们大多数人更有可能拥有严肃的爱好。
Slow-motion multitasking among creative people is ubiquitous.
[AI] 在有创造力的人中，慢动作多任务处理是无处不在的。
So. why?
[AI] 所以为什么？
I think there are three reasons.
[AI] 我认为有三个原因。
And the first is the simplest.
[AI] 第一个是最简单的。
Creativity often comes when you take an idea from its original context
[AI] 当你从最初的环境中接受一个想法时，创造力就会产生
and you move it somewhere else.
[AI] 然后你把它移到别的地方。
It's easier to think outside the box
[AI] 跳出框框思考更容易
if you spend your time clambering from one box into another.
[AI] 如果你花时间从一个箱子爬到另一个箱子里。
For an example of this. consider the original eureka moment.
[AI] 举个例子。想想最初的尤里卡时刻。
Archimedes -- he's wrestling with a difficult problem.
[AI] 阿基米德——他正在努力解决一个难题。
And he realizes. in a flash.
[AI] 他意识到。转眼间。
he can solve it. using the displacement of water.
[AI] 他能解决它。利用水的置换。
And if you believe the story.
[AI] 如果你相信这个故事。
this idea comes to him as he's taking a bath.
[AI] 他在洗澡时想到了这个主意。
lowering himself in. and he's watching the water level rise and fall.
[AI] 把自己放下。他看着水位的升降。
And if solving a problem while having a bath isn't multitasking.
[AI] 如果在洗澡时解决问题不是多任务。
I don't know what is.
[AI] 我不知道是什么。
The second reason that multitasking can work
[AI] 多任务处理可以工作的第二个原因
is that learning to do one thing well
[AI] 那就是学会把一件事做好吗
can often help you do something else.
[AI] 经常可以帮助你做其他事情。
Any athlete can tell you about the benefits of cross-training.
[AI] 任何运动员都可以告诉你交叉训练的好处。
It's possible to cross-train your mind. too.
[AI] 可以交叉训练你的思维。也
A few years ago. researchers took 18 randomly chosen medical students
[AI] 几年前。研究人员随机抽取了18名医科学生
and they enrolled them in a course at the Philadelphia Museum of Art.
[AI] 他们让他们参加了费城艺术博物馆的一门课程。
where they learned to criticize and analyze works of visual art.
[AI] 在那里他们学会了批评和分析视觉艺术作品。
And at the end of the course.
[AI] 在课程结束时。
these students were compared with a control group
[AI] 这些学生与对照组进行了比较
of their fellow medical students.
[AI] 他们的医学同学。
And the ones who had taken the art course
[AI] 还有那些上过艺术课的人
had become substantially better at performing tasks
[AI] 在执行任务方面有了很大的进步
such as diagnosing diseases of the eye by analyzing photographs.
[AI] 比如通过分析照片来诊断眼部疾病。
They'd become better eye doctors.
[AI] 他们会成为更好的眼科医生。
So if we want to become better at what we do.
[AI] 因此，如果我们想在我们所做的事情上做得更好。
maybe we should spend some time doing something else.
[AI] 也许我们应该花点时间做点别的。
even if the two fields appear to be as completely distinct
[AI] 即使这两个字段看起来完全不同
as ophthalmology and the history of art.
[AI] 作为眼科学和艺术史。
And if you'd like an example of this.
[AI] 如果你想举个例子。
should we go for a less intimidating example than Einstein? OK.
[AI] 我们应该选择一个没有爱因斯坦那么可怕的例子吗？好啊
Michael Crichton. creator of "Jurassic Park" and "E.R."
[AI] 迈克尔·克莱顿。《侏罗纪公园》和《急诊室》的创作者
So in the 1970s. he originally trained as a doctor.
[AI] 所以在20世纪70年代。他最初受训成为一名医生。
but then he wrote novels
[AI] 但后来他写了小说
and he directed the original "Westworld" movie.
[AI] 他执导了《西世界》的原创电影。
But also. and this is less well-known.
[AI] 而且。而这一点不太为人所知。
he also wrote nonfiction books.
[AI] 他还写非小说类书籍。
about art. about medicine. about computer programming.
[AI] 关于艺术。关于医学。关于计算机编程。
So in 1995. he enjoyed the fruits of all this variety
[AI] 1995年也是如此。他喜欢吃各种各样的水果
by penning the world's most commercially successful book.
[AI] 写了世界上最成功的商业书籍。
And the world's most commercially successful TV series.
[AI] 以及世界上最成功的商业电视连续剧。
And the world's most commercially successful movie.
[AI] 世界上最成功的商业电影。
In 1996. he did it all over again.
[AI] 1996年。他把一切都重新做了一遍。
There's a third reason
[AI] 还有第三个原因
why slow-motion multitasking can help us solve problems.
[AI] 为什么慢动作多任务处理可以帮助我们解决问题。
It can provide assistance when we're stuck.
[AI] 它可以在我们陷入困境时提供帮助。
This can't happen in an instant.
[AI] 这不可能在一瞬间发生。
So. imagine that feeling of working on a crossword puzzle
[AI] 所以想象一下做填字游戏的那种感觉
and you can't figure out the answer.
[AI] 而你无法找到答案。
and the reason you can't is because the wrong answer is stuck in your head.
[AI] 你不能这么做的原因是因为错误的答案卡在你的脑海里。
It's very easy -- just go and do something else.
[AI] 这很简单，去做点别的吧。
You know. switch topics. switch context.
[AI] 你知道的。切换主题。切换上下文。
you'll forget the wrong answer
[AI] 你会忘记错误的答案的
and that gives the right answer space to pop into the front of your mind.
[AI] 这就给了你正确的答案，让它在你的脑海中闪现。
But on the slower timescale that interests me.
[AI] 但是在我感兴趣的较慢的时间尺度上。
being stuck is a much more serious thing.
[AI] 被卡住是更严重的事情。
You get turned down for funding.
[AI] 你的资助被拒绝了。
Your cell cultures won't grow. your rockets keep crashing.
[AI] 你的细胞培养不会生长。你的火箭不断坠毁。
Nobody wants to publish you fantasy novel about a school for wizards.
[AI] 没有人想出版你关于巫师学校的幻想小说。
Or maybe you just can't find the solution to the problem that you're working on.
[AI] 或者你就是找不到解决你正在研究的问题的方法。
And being stuck like that means stasis. stress.
[AI] 像那样被卡住意味着停滞。强调
possibly even depression.
[AI] 甚至可能是抑郁症。
But if you have another exciting. challenging project to work on.
[AI] 但如果你有另一个令人兴奋的。具有挑战性的工作项目。
being stuck on one is just an opportunity to do something else.
[AI] 被困在其中只是一个做其他事情的机会。
We could all get stuck sometimes. even Albert Einstein.
[AI] 有时我们都会陷入困境。甚至阿尔伯特·爱因斯坦。
Ten years after the original. miraculous year that I described.
[AI] 十年后的最初。我描述的奇迹般的一年。
Einstein was putting together the pieces of his theory of general relativity.
[AI] 爱因斯坦正在整理他的广义相对论。
his greatest achievement.
[AI] 他最大的成就。
And he was exhausted.
[AI] 他筋疲力尽了。
And so he turned to an easier problem.
[AI] 于是他转向了一个更简单的问题。
He proposed the stimulated emission of radiation.
[AI] 他提出了辐射的受激发射。
Which. as you may know. is the S in laser.
[AI] 哪一个你可能知道。是激光中的S。
So he's laying down the theoretical foundation for the laser beam.
[AI] 因此，他为激光束奠定了理论基础。
and then. while he's doing that.
[AI] 然后。当他这么做的时候。
he moves back to general relativity. and he's refreshed.
[AI] 他又回到了广义相对论。他恢复了精神。
He sees what the theory implies --
[AI] 他明白这个理论的含义--
that the universe isn't static.
[AI] 宇宙不是静止的。
It's expanding.
[AI] 它在扩张。
It's an idea so staggering.
[AI] 这是一个惊人的想法。
Einstein can't bring himself to believe it for years.
[AI] 爱因斯坦多年来都无法让自己相信这一点。
Look. if you get stuck
[AI] 看如果你被卡住了
and you get the ball rolling on laser beams.
[AI] 你可以让球在激光束上滚动。
you're in pretty good shape.
[AI] 你的身体很好。
(Laughter)
[AI] （众笑）
So. that's the case for slow-motion multitasking.
[AI] 所以这就是慢动作多任务处理的情况。
And I'm not promising that it's going to turn you into Einstein.
[AI] 我不能保证它会把你变成爱因斯坦。
I'm not even promising it's going to turn you into Michael Crichton.
[AI] 我甚至不敢保证会把你变成迈克尔·克莱顿。
But it is a powerful way to organize our creative lives.
[AI] 但这是组织我们创造性生活的一种强有力的方式。
But there's a problem.
[AI] 但是有个问题。
How do we stop all of these projects becoming completely overwhelming?
[AI] 我们如何阻止所有这些项目变得势不可挡？
How do we keep all these ideas straight in our minds?
[AI] 我们如何在头脑中保持这些想法的清晰？
Well. here's a simple solution. a practical solution
[AI] 好这里有一个简单的解决方案。切实可行的解决办法
from the great American choreographer. Twyla Tharp.
[AI] 来自伟大的美国编舞。特维拉·瑟普。
Over the last few decades.
[AI] 在过去的几十年里。
she's blurred boundaries. mixed genres. won prizes.
[AI] 她模糊了界限。混合体裁。获奖。
danced to the music of everybody. from Philip Glass to Billy Joel.
[AI] 随着每个人的音乐跳舞。从菲利普·格拉斯到比利·乔尔。
She's written three books.
[AI] 她写了三本书。
I mean. she's a slow-motion multitasker. of course she is.
[AI] 我是说。她是个慢动作多任务者。她当然是。
She says. "You have to be all things.
[AI] 她说。“你必须是一切。
Why exclude?
[AI] 为什么要排除？
You have to be everything."
[AI] 你必须成为一切。"
And Tharp's method
[AI] 和Tharp的方法
for preventing all of these different projects from becoming overwhelming
[AI] 防止所有这些不同的项目变得势不可挡
is a simple one.
[AI] 这是一个简单的问题。
She gives each project a big cardboard box.
[AI] 她给每个项目一个大纸箱。
writes the name of the project on the side of the box.
[AI] 将项目名称写在框的侧面。
And into it. she tosses DVDs and books. magazine cuttings.
[AI] 并将其融入其中。她扔DVD和书。杂志剪辑。
theater programs. physical objects.
[AI] 戏剧节目。物理对象。
really anything that's provided a source of creative inspiration.
[AI] 任何能提供创造性灵感的东西。
And she writes.
[AI] 她写。
"The box means I never have to worry about forgetting.
[AI] “这个盒子意味着我永远不用担心忘记。
One of the biggest fears for a creative person
[AI] 一个有创造力的人最大的恐惧之一
is that some brilliant idea will get lost
[AI] 是不是有些好主意会消失
because you didn't write it down and put it in a safe place.
[AI] 因为你没有把它写下来放在一个安全的地方。
I don't worry about that.
[AI] 我不担心这个。
Because I know where to find it.
[AI] 因为我知道在哪里能找到它。
It's all in the box."
[AI] 都在盒子里。"
You can manage many ideas like this.
[AI] 你可以管理许多这样的想法。
either in physical boxes or in their digital equivalents.
[AI] 无论是在物理框中还是在其数字等价物中。
So. I would like to urge you
[AI] 所以我想敦促你
to embrace the art of slow-motion multitasking.
[AI] 拥抱慢动作多任务处理的艺术。
Not because you're in a hurry.
[AI] 不是因为你赶时间。
but because you're in no hurry at all.
[AI] 但因为你一点也不着急。
And I want to give you one final example.
[AI] 我想给你们最后一个例子。
my favorite example.
[AI] 我最喜欢的例子。
Charles Darwin.
[AI] 查尔斯·达尔文。
A man whose slow-burning multitasking is so staggering.
[AI] 一个缓慢完成多项任务的人是如此令人震惊。
I need a diagram to explain it all to you.
[AI] 我需要一张图表来向你解释这一切。
We know what Darwin was doing at different times.
[AI] 我们知道达尔文在不同的时期做了什么。
because the creativity researchers Howard Gruber and Sara Davis
[AI] 因为创意研究者霍华德·格鲁伯和莎拉·戴维斯
have analyzed his diaries and his notebooks.
[AI] 分析了他的日记和笔记本。
So. when he left school. age of 18.
[AI] 所以当他离开学校时。18岁。
he was initially interested in two fields.
[AI] 他最初对两个领域感兴趣。
zoology and geology.
[AI] 动物学和地质学。
Pretty soon. he signed up to be the onboard naturalist on the "Beagle."
[AI] 很快。他报名成为“小猎犬”号上的船上博物学家
This is the ship that eventually took five years
[AI] 这艘船最终花了五年时间
to sail all the way around the southern oceans of the Earth.
[AI] 环绕地球南部海洋航行。
stopping at the Galápagos. passing through the Indian ocean.
[AI] 在加拉帕戈斯停留。穿过印度洋。
While he was on the "Beagle." he began researching coral reefs.
[AI] 当他在“小猎犬”号上的时候他开始研究珊瑚礁。
This is a great synergy between his two interests
[AI] 这是他两种兴趣之间的巨大协同作用
in zoology and geology.
[AI] 在动物学和地质学方面。
and it starts to get him thinking about slow processes.
[AI] 这让他开始思考缓慢的过程。
But when he gets back from the voyage.
[AI] 但是当他航行回来的时候。
his interests start to expand even further: psychology. botany;
[AI] 他的兴趣开始进一步扩展：心理学。植物学
for the rest of his life.
[AI] 他的余生。
he's moving backwards and forwards between these different fields.
[AI] 他在不同的领域之间来回移动。
He never quite abandons any of them.
[AI] 他从不完全抛弃他们中的任何一个。
In 1837. he begins work on two very interesting projects.
[AI] 1837年。他开始从事两个非常有趣的项目。
One of them: earthworms.
[AI] 其中之一是蚯蚓。
The other. a little notebook which he titles
[AI] 其他的。他写的一本小笔记本
"The transmutation of species."
[AI] “物种的蜕变。”
Then. Darwin starts studying my field. economics.
[AI] 然后达尔文开始研究我的领域。经济学
He reads a book by the economist Thomas Malthus.
[AI] 他读了经济学家托马斯·马尔萨斯的一本书。
And he has his eureka moment.
[AI] 他有自己的尤里卡时刻。
In a flash. he realizes how species could emerge and evolve slowly.
[AI] 转眼间。他意识到物种是如何慢慢出现和进化的。
through this process of the survival of the fittest.
[AI] 通过这一过程，适者生存。
It all comes to him. he writes it all down.
[AI] 这一切都发生在他身上。他把一切都写了下来。
every single important element of the theory of evolution.
[AI] 进化论的每一个重要元素。
in that notebook.
[AI] 在那个笔记本里。
But then. a new project.
[AI] 但是后来。一个新项目。
His son William is born.
[AI] 他的儿子威廉出生了。
Well. there's a natural experiment right there.
[AI] 好这里有一个自然实验。
you get to observe the development of a human infant.
[AI] 你可以观察人类婴儿的发育。
So immediately. Darwin starts making notes.
[AI] 所以马上。达尔文开始做笔记。
Now. of course. he's still working on the theory of evolution
[AI] 现在当然他还在研究进化论
and the development of the human infant.
[AI] 以及人类婴儿的发育。
But during all of this.
[AI] 但在这一切过程中。
he realizes he doesn't really know enough about taxonomy.
[AI] 他意识到自己对分类学的了解还不够。
So he starts studying that.
[AI] 所以他开始研究这个。
And in the end. he spends eight years becoming the world's leading expert
[AI] 最后。他花了八年时间成为世界领先的专家
on barnacles.
[AI] 在藤壶上。
Then. "Natural Selection."
[AI] 然后“自然选择。”
A book that he's to continue working on for his entire life. he never finishes it.
[AI] 一本他将终生继续创作的书。他从来没有完成过。
"Origin of Species" is finally published
[AI] 《物种起源》终于出版了
20 years after Darwin set out all the basic elements.
[AI] 20年后，达尔文提出了所有基本要素。
Then. the "Descent of Man." controversial book.
[AI] 然后“人类的后裔”有争议的书。
And then. the book about the development of the human infant.
[AI] 然后。关于人类婴儿发育的书。
The one that was inspired when he could see his son. William.
[AI] 当他能看到他的儿子时，他受到了启发。威廉。
crawling on the sitting room floor in front of him.
[AI] 在他面前的客厅地板上爬行。
When the book was published. William was 37 years old.
[AI] 这本书出版时。威廉37岁。
And all this time.
[AI] 一直以来。
Darwin's working on earthworms.
[AI] 达尔文正在研究蚯蚓。
He fills his billiard room with earthworms in pots. with glass covers.
[AI] 他用壶里的蚯蚓填满他的台球室。用玻璃罩。
He shines lights on them. to see if they'll respond.
[AI] 他把灯照在他们身上。看看他们是否会回应。
He holds a hot poker next to them. to see if they move away.
[AI] 他在他们旁边拿着一把热扑克。看看他们是否离开。
He chews tobacco and --
[AI] 他嚼烟草和面包--
(Blows)
[AI] （打击）
He blows on the earthworms to see if they have a sense of smell.
[AI] 他吹蚯蚓，看它们是否有嗅觉。
He even plays the bassoon at the earthworms.
[AI] 他甚至在蚯蚓乐队演奏巴松管。
I like to think of this great man
[AI] 我喜欢想起这位伟人
when he's tired. he's stressed.
[AI] 当他累的时候。他压力很大。
he's anxious about the reception of his book "The Descent of Man."
[AI] 他很担心他的书《人类的起源》会被接受
You or I might log into Facebook or turn on the television.
[AI] 你或我可能登录Facebook或打开电视。
Darwin would go into the billiard room to relax
[AI] 达尔文会走进台球室放松一下
by studying the earthworms intensely.
[AI] 通过对蚯蚓的深入研究。
And that's why it's appropriate that one of his last great works
[AI] 这就是为什么他最后一部伟大的作品
is the "Formation of Vegetable Mould Through The Action of Worms."
[AI] 是“通过蠕虫的作用形成蔬菜霉菌”
(Laughter)
[AI] （众笑）
He worked upon that book for 44 years.
[AI] 他为那本书工作了44年。
We don't live in the 19th century anymore.
[AI] 我们不再生活在19世纪了。
I don't think any of us could sit
[AI] 我想我们谁也坐不了
on our creative or scientific projects for 44 years.
[AI] 在我们44年的创新或科学项目上。
But we do have something to learn from the great slow-motion multitaskers.
[AI] 但我们确实可以从伟大的慢动作多任务处理者那里学到一些东西。
From Einstein and Darwin to Michael Crichton and Twyla Tharp.
[AI] 从爱因斯坦和达尔文到迈克尔·克莱顿和特维拉·瑟普。
The modern world seems to present us with a choice.
[AI] 现代世界似乎给了我们一个选择。
If we're not going to fast-twitch from browser window to browser window.
[AI] 如果我们不打算在浏览器窗口之间快速切换。
we have to live like a hermit.
[AI] 我们必须像隐士一样生活。
focus on one thing to the exclusion of everything else.
[AI] 把注意力集中在一件事上，而把其他一切都排除在外。
I think that's a false dilemma.
[AI] 我认为这是一个错误的困境。
We can make multitasking work for us.
[AI] 我们可以让多重任务为我们工作。
unleashing our natural creativity.
[AI] 释放我们天生的创造力。
We just need to slow it down.
[AI] 我们只需要放慢速度。
So ...
[AI] 所以
Make a list of your projects.
[AI] 列出你的项目清单。
Put down your phone.
[AI] 放下你的电话。
Pick up a couple of cardboard boxes.
[AI] 拿起几个纸板箱。
And get to work.
[AI] 然后开始工作。
Thank you very much.
[AI] 非常感谢你。
(Applause)
[AI] （掌声）